Contact

2144060635 (Home) darlingtonigbokwe@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/darlingtoni (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

excellent people skills

Good communication and observation

happy to work as part of team

Languages

Igbo

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

QPR Suicide Prevention Gatekeeper Program

CPR &AED

OSHA for General Industry safety and health

Human Subject Protection

Honors-Awards

Master silver

Student lead(high school captain)
Neatest and Best Behaved student
Dean's list with Distinction

Darlington Igbokwe

RN- psychiatric Emergency Center at JPS Health Network Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex

Summary

I have a passion for nursing and helping to prevent disease, restore health, alleviate suffering and promote independence in patients as well as helping them to maintain their dignity. I want to explore the other fields in nursing such as travel nursing and specializing in public health nursing as well attain my certification as an occupational health nurse where i can be privileged in promoting health education, counseling, conducting environmental surveillance for health hazards and providing direct nursing care to the employees and the public.in all, education is an empowerment and i strongly believe is the foundation of building a better life and education possibilities.

Experience

JPS Health Network RN- Psychiatric Emergency Center May 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

- -Performs a complete assessment of a psychiatric patient and other various duties and direct care with regard to age and developmental stage, presenting complaint, and pertinent history.
- -Delivers nursing care to assigned group of psychiatric patients including education directed towards identified knowledge deficits, treatment planning, pain management and discharge planning utilizing the nursing process.
- -Delivers quality nursing care while minimizing the risk of infection, contamination, harm, or injury.
- -Participates in the performance improvement process within the Network, Hospital, and department.

- -Anticipates deteriorating life sign patterns or equipment malfunctions and takes appropriate action.
- -Maintains accurate, detailed reports and records.
- -Modifies patient treatment plans as indicated by patients' responses and conditions.
- -Monitors, records and reports symptoms and changes in patients' conditions.
- -Performs other related duties as assigned.

Hickory Trail Hospital, L.P.
Psychiatric Nurse
April 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 5 months)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

- Coordinates, and evaluates patient care through collaborative efforts with health team members in accordance with the nursing process and the standards of care and practices.
- Provide nursing interventions and management of acute children, adolescents and adult patients as prescribed by the physician, and serves as Licensed Independent Practitioner during restraint, seclusion, and behavioral crisis intervention.
- Provide supervision and guidance of direct care workers as charge nurse, assures milieu management and quality delivery of treatment to assigned patients.
- -Provides patient specific treatment, adheres to patient safety standards, assures patient rights, prevents and identifies abuse, and oversees the quality of behavioral interventions.

Dallas Behavioral Health Hospital Psychiatric Nurse March 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 10 months) Desoto, Texas

- # Performs a complete assessment of a psychiatric patient and other various duties and direct care with regard to age and developmental stage, presenting complaint, and pertinent history.
- # Delivers nursing care to assigned group of psychiatric patients including education directed towards identified knowledge deficits, treatment planning, pain management and discharge planning utilizing the nursing process.
- # Delivers quality nursing care while minimizing the risk of infection, contamination, harm, or injury.
- # Participates in the performance improvement process within the Network, Hospital, and department.
- # Anticipates deteriorating life sign patterns or equipment malfunctions and takes appropriate action.
- # Maintains accurate, detailed reports and records.
- # Modifies patient treatment plans as indicated by patients' responses and conditions.
- # Monitors, records and reports symptoms and changes in patients' conditions.
- # Performs other related duties as assigned.

HCR ManorCare Registered Nurse January 2017 - July 2017 (7 months) Bedford, Texas

- # [Provide high-quality patient care through; accurate assessment, dispensing of medication, intravenous initiation and maintenance, oxygen therapy, wound care, ostomy care, Foley insertion and care, respiration therapy, diabetic management/insulin administration]
- # [Responsible for carrying out new orders, updating lab values, and reporting them to a doctor]
- # [Coordinates and oversees new patient admission, transfer, and discharge paperwork]

Education

The University of Texas at Arlington RN to BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2019 - 2020)

Mountain View College
Prerequisite For RN-BSN · (2019 - 2019)

Tarrant County College
Prerequisite for RN-BSN · (2017 - 2018)

School of Nursing Abia State University Teaching Hospital Diploma in Nursing/General Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2010 - 2014)